Frank G. Speck Papers 1903-1950 Mss.Ms.Coll.126
American Philosophical Society
- Subcollection I. Frank G. Speck Papers, 1897-1950; 10 linear feet
  - Series I. Research Material, 1903-1950; 8.25 linear feet
    - III. Northeast (ill-defined area west of Mississippi, north of corn-growing limit, south to approximately Mason-Dixon Line)
      - C. Delaware [Lenape]
        - 2. Oklahoma Delaware
          - Oklahoma Delaware -- y. letters from, 1941; III(9C2y); 12 items; Wilson, Reuben (Box 6)
            Letters concerning museum specimens, model, and sketch of Big House. March 18, 1941, 1p. and enc., concerning masks, other specimens, sketch of Delaware church (1925); April 23, 1941, 1p., concerning Big House and "Messing 1941, 1p. sketch of mask and costume of Messing; May 2, 1941, 2p., concerning Messing; May 7, 1941, post card of Fred Washington to Speck concerning Wilson; Sept. 12, 1941, 1p., concerning a mortar; Oct. 11, 1941, 1p., concerning Lenape words and Big House model. List of articles and prices; 1p. 2 queries of Speck on cards with Wilson's answers. Images note: photographs of Reuben Wilson, Washington County, Oklahoma Delaware; sketches of peace pipe, tobacco pouch, homing spoon, canoe, paddle, figure with bear hide cover and mask.
            F&S 937
            - Reuben Wilson (Weekpakehing), 1941
          - Oklahoma Delaware -- z. letters from, 1933-1944; III(9C2z); 36 items; War Eagle (Box 6)
            Concerning War Eagle's collecting legends and traditions; his obtaining museum specimens; information on peyote and on Big House; his health; reservation and national Indian affairs; some mention of Pawnee, Nanticoke, etc. See various other documents listed separately, but transmitted with these letters. Includes the following tales: snow boy tale, boy captive of bear, trickster tale, Pawnee witch story.
            F&S 932
        - 3. Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- a. letters from, 1932-1948; III(8C3a); 19 items; Moses, Jesse, Jr. (Box 5)
            Letters: April 7, 1934, 1p., concerning obtaining data; Oct. 5, 1940, 4p., concerning reservation activities; Dec. 11, 1941, 4p., reservation affairs; Nov. 23, 1942, (typed copy?), 1p., concerning Speck (1942) and Indian affairs; Nov. 13, 1944, 5p., wrongs to Indians and miscellaneous; Nov. 29, 1944, 4p., concerning Lenni Lenape and data Moses is gathering; Dec. 3, 1944, 8p., same subject; Dec. 7, 1944, 4p., (typed), Story of Nick (Peters?) and white captives; Sept. 7, 1945, 3p., concerning Delaware affairs, speculations on Delaware religion, concept of Great Spirit and conversion to Christianity; Aug. 4, 1947, 4p., miscellaneous Cayuga and Delaware affairs; Nov. 31, 1945, 6p., sends treaty of 1777 of British and Indians at Detroit, discusses manufacture of museum specimens; Sept. 7, 1948, 3p., miscellaneous, discusses meeting with Mormon missionaries; ca. 19431944, 1p., fragment of letter. Speck field notes taken from Jesse Moses, 1944, 3p. Images note: 7 photographs of old and young Jesse Moses. F&S 893
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- b. [no entry], III(8C3b) (Box 5)
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- c. Miscellaneous notes, 1938-1945; III(8C3c); 16 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 5)
            Abstract of report on University of Pennsylvania grant (Bear Ceremony), 1p. Ethnographic notes, 17p. Letters: M. R. Harrington (Southwest Museum) to Speck, March 11, 1938, T.L.S., 1p., concerning his MS. on Delaware (1945a) and comparisons with Minsi; Charles Edgar Gilliam to Speck, Oct. 22, 1945, A.L.S., 2p., concerning the celestial bear theme, refers to William Byrd's attributing aphrodisiacal powers to bear meat and Gilliam suggests that the winter ceremony thus insures birth of children at harvest when there will be food; Paul A. W. Wallace to Speck, Sept. 11, 1945, T.L.S., 1p., concerns Joseph Montour and his return to his native religion. Images note: ink sketch of shaft and cup. F&S 912
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- d. Stories, 1934-1943; III(8C3d); 11 items; Hill, Jasper "Big White Owl" (Box 5)
            Two narratives by an acculturated Moravian Delaware and accompanying letters (seeking and transmitting information): Hill to Frank G. Speck, Mar. 15, 1934; April, 1934; April 28, 1934; Feb. 28, 1943. Images note: photograph of Big White Owl, sketch by Big White Owl of logo. F&S 892
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- e. Notes on life and geneology of Joseph Montour, 1932; III(8C3e); 3 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 5)
            Includes chart of succession of chiefs, 1855-1937; data from Joseph Montour (biographical). 3p. biography of Nicodemus Peters (1859-1938).
            F&S 916
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- f. Field notes, 1945; III(8C3f); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 5)
            Linguistic materials: names of objects, materia medica names. Images note: 2 pencil sketches by John Witthoft of bow.
            F&S 1177
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- g. Texts narrated by, 1931-1936; III(8C3g); 7 items; Montour, Josiah (Box 6)
            Six texts in Delaware with interlinear translations.
            F&S 1173
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- h. Field notes, 1946; III(8C3h); 4 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 6)
            Field trip with Anthony F. C. Wallace and Mr. and Mrs. E. S. Carpenter: Delaware text, no translation, from Josiah Montour; Delaware, Cayuga, and Mohawk words.
            F&S 1181
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- i. Field notes, 1936; III(8C3i); 2items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 6)
            Ethnographic and linguistic notes; concerns ceremonies and text. Letter of Nicodemus Peters to Speck, March 2, 1936, concerning masks and a turtle rattle.
            F&S 907
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- j. Hoop game, 1944-1945; III(8C3j); 3 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 6)
            Cayuga hoop game data from Deskaheh. Typed D. description of Delaware-Munsee hoop game. Postal card, Nov. 24, 1944, of Ernest S. Dodge to Speck, concerning reference to hoop game in Morgan's League of the Iroquois (1851).
            F&S 559
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- k. Letters from and concerning, 1935-1939; III(8C3k); 15 items; Peters, Nick (Box 6)
            Letters of Peters to Speck concerning museum specimens being obtained by Peters: Jan. 3, 1938; April 11, 1938; May 1, 1938; and no date. Letters concerning death of Peters and his collecting museum specimens: Irma Peters to Speck, Nov. 23, 1938, 2p., Margaret Vanderberg to Speck, Jan. 8, 1938; ? to Speck, n.d., concerning Peters data on executions; three letters of Frank Siebert to Speck, July 24, 1938, 2p., Nov. 20, 1938, 2p., and June 25, 1939, all concerning linguistic field work with Peters and museum specimens. 4p. biographical data concerning Nekatcit.
            F&S 898
          - Canadian (Grand River, Ont.) Delaware -- l. letters from, 1934-1935; III(8C3l); 4 items; John, Samuel (Box 6)
            Three letters concerning John's Tutelo background and Speck's visit to Canadian Delawares. Sept. 4, 1934, 3p.; Jan. 8, 1935, 4p.; June 2, 1935, 2p.
            F&S 3821
          - General New England -- a. "Letters of the Indians", III(10D1a); 1 item; Butler, Eva L. (Box 6)
            29 letters of seventeenth-century Indians, principally from archives in Connecticut State Library. A pamphlet issued by Industrial Arts Cooperative Service. Contents and index.
            F&S 343
      - D. New England Algonkians (also including Algonkians of Nova Scotia and New Brunswick)
        - 1. General New England
          - General New England -- b. "Colonial Letters of our Ancestors", III(10D1b); 1 item; Butler, Eva L. (Box 6)
            19 letters of seventeenth-century colonial Connecticut, principally from Connecticut State Library. A pamphlet issued by Industrial Arts Cooperative Service. Contents and index.
            F&S 342
          - General New England -- c. Tribal Maps, III(10D1c) (Box 6)
            [see map files]
          - General New England -- d. "Ethnobotany and Ethnozoology of the New England Indians", III(10D1d); 1 item; Butler, Eva L. (Box 6)
            90p. of ethnobotanical references, 29p. of ethnozoological references found in a 3p. bibliography of seventeenth and eighteenth century sources.
            F&S 331
          - General New England -- e. Bibliography of New England Tribes, III(10D1e); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 6)
            Nineteenth-century printed references; some twentieth-century.
            F&S 2092
        - 2. Penobscot
          - Penobscot -- a. "Bird Lore of the Northern Indians", III(11D2a); 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            A faculty public lecture, University of Pennsylvania. Images note: photomechanical print of Penobscot around campfire. F&S 2925
          - Penobscot -- b. Miscellaneous Notes, 1912-1946; III(11D2b); 55 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            Correspondence relating to Speck's Penobscot work also, letters from informants, and various documents. Speck to Poland E. Nelson (Needahbeh), May 14, 1928, T.L., c.c., 1p., concerning drum for exhibit. Franz Boas, May 31, 1940, T.L.S., 1p. John M. Cooper, Aug. 11, 1940, A.L.S., 2p. William B. Goodwin, Nov. 9 and 21, 1940, T.L.S., 6p. and 1p. E. V. McCollum, May 24, 1940, T.L.S., 1p. Roland E. Nelson, April 28, 1940, A.L.S., 2p. J. Dyneley Prince, May 18, 1940, A.L.S., 2p. all concerning Penobscot Man; Clifford P. Wilson to Speck, Dec. 29, 1937 and Feb. 2, 1938, T.L.S., 1p., both concerning Moosehair embroidery; Edward Reman, May 19, 1940, T.L.S., 2p., concerning Norse influence on Penobscot; Carrie A. Lyford, May 9, 1941, A.L.S., lp., concerning moose-wool controversy and Ann Stimson's report; Ann Stimson, n.d. (1941?) T.L.S., 1p., letter of thanks; Henry Noyes Otis, March 20, 1939, A.L.S., 2p. concerning genealogy of Indians named Sias on Cape Cod (Speck marked this Penobscot). Princess Pretty Woman, April 13, 1946, 1p., concerning her dress. Dorothy Panco, April 27, 1946, A.L.S., 2p., concerning Princess Pretty Woman's dress (both are Indians). Poland W. Mann, Nov. 8, 1943, A.L.S., 2p., concerning site of Indian occupancy according to Penobscot tradition; Ryuzo Torii, July 26, 1943, T.L.S., 1p., letter of introduction. 1p. typed transcript from printed D., 5p. transcript of agreements of Indians of Nova Scotia and English, Aug. 15, 1749, and 2p. transcript of agreement of July 13, 1727 (letter of transmittal, Lloyd Price to Miss MacDonald, Sept. 24, 1936, A.L.S., 1p.). Ann K. Stimson, Moose Wool (A.D., 2p. and 3 1p. typed copies) and Climbing Powers of the American Mink (A.D. 2p. and 3 1p. typed copies). Miscellaneous: 14p. and 17p. of field notes, Malecite and Penobscot. 9p. songs, kinship, totem, medicine, social units, 4p. Penobscot words and their cultural use; 10p. misc., and B cards. Images note: 10 sketches of face painting. F&S 2932
          - Penobscot -- c. Penobscot religion, 1910; III(11D2c); 15 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            An introductory statement in 4p. with a 5p. revision; also, 8L. of miscellaneous notes.
            F&S 2938
          - Penobscot -- d. Penobscot field notes, 1909-1911; III(11D2d); 32 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            An introduction and description of canoemaking; miscellaneous ethnographic field notes; data on face painting, etc. Images note: 11 contact prints, 3 albumen prints, 42 sketches of canoe-making, face painting, double curve design, portraits, snow snake, game diagrams. F&S 2927
          - Penobscot -- e. MS. of Penobscot Man, n.d.; III(11D2e); 46 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            77p. of manuscript for Speck (1940a); plates (figures); Bp. letter of Frank (Siebert?) to Speck, May 29, 1939, concerning his Penobscot MS. Images note: 112 ink sketches of mocassins, baskets, utensils, bowls, spoons, show shoes, combs, shelters, bark implements.
            F&S 2937
          - Penobscot -- f. Counting and measuring, III(11D2f); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            Material not printed in Penobscot Man (1940a): 4p. on counting; 2p, on names of acculturated objects; 4p. on manners and dispositions; 2p. on attitudes and behavior.
            F&S 2926
          - Penobscot -- g. Scientific Penobscot Alphabet, n.d.; III(11D2g); 1 item; Swadesh, Morris and Charles F. Voegelin (Box 7)
            Scientific Penobscot alphabet
            F&S 2946
          - Penobscot -- h. letters from, 1936-1941; III(12D2h); 14 items; Echstorm, F. H. (Box 8)
            Letters concerning publication and criticism of Penobscot Man; ethnographic data on Penobscot; relationship of Penobscot-Mohegan and Mahican; also, comparison of Zuñi-Navajo and Red Paint; Tutelo.
            F&S 2920
          - Penobscot -- i. [no entry], III(12D2i) (Box 8)
          - Penobscot -- j. [no entry], III(12D2j) (Box 8)
          - Penobscot -- k. Penobscot sayings, n.d.; III(12D2k); 1 item; Needahbeh (Box 8)
            Miscellany not used in book (1940).
            F&S 2939
          - Penobscot -- l. House furnishings, 1935; III(12D2l); 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 8)
            Some parts not used in Speck (1940a).
            F&S 2928
          - Penobscot -- m. Hunting morality, n.d.; III(12D2m); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 8)
            Religious aspect of hunting.
            F&S 2929
          - Penobscot -- n. [no entry], III(12D2n) (Box 8)
          - Penobscot -- o. Notes on Penobscot Social Organization, n.d.; III(12D2o); 6 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 8)
            Charts on family, its size, totem, etc., 2p.; 2p. on family history and names; 39p. miscellaneous notes, 1918, including text interlinear translation; Micmac data.
            F&S 2933
          - Penobscot -- p. [no entry], III(12D2p) (Box 8)
          - Penobscot -- q. Penobscot calendar system, 1916-1928; III(12D2q); 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 8)
            Notebook on calendar and seasons for hunting and sugar-making. Letter (part c.c.) of A. L. Kroeber to Speck, together with 1p. cluestionnaire on comparative calendars.
            F&S 2936
          - Penobscot -- r. Penobscot animal lore, 1924; III(12D2r); 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 8)
            Data; cf. Speck (1935b) (?).
            F&S 2934
          - Penobscot -- s. Penobscot Art and the Penobscot texts, III(12D2s); 5 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 8)
            Material not used in Penobscot Man because of duplication in Speck (1927b). Images note: 6 photgraphs of wampum, tobacco pouch, mocassins, beaded cuffs, woman's hair ornament; 118 ink sketches of double curve designs. F&S 2935
            - Buckskin tobacco pouch, n.d.
          - Penobscot -- t. Penobscot texts (I), 1928; III(12D2t); 19 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 8)
            Texts with interlinear translations; several English texts; typed versions of texts in English.
            F&S 2945
          - Penobscot -- t. Penobscot texts (II), 1928; III(12D2t); 5 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 8)
        - 3. Malecite
          - Malecite -- a. Malacite Dance, 1936; III(13D3a); 4 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 8)
            Text with interlinear translation; notes; musical score.
            F&S 2099
          - Malecite -- b. Passamaquoddy-Malecite Dictionary, 1921; III(13D3b); 1 item; Prince, J. Dyneley (Box 8)
            Indian-English, arranged according to English alphabet; also, English-Indian. Based on 1911 collection of Passamaquoddy texts printed in Prince (1921).
            F&S 2649
          - Malecite -- c. [no entry], III(13D3c) (Box 9)
          - Malecite -- d. Miscellaneous Malecite field notes, 1917-1948; III(13D3d); 19 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            7p. of slips containing Malecite words; 1p. printed map of St. John's River with Malecite villages marked; 12p. Malecite terms (with a few Penobscot items), 1948: 12p. unpublished notes on hunting territories. Letter of J. Clarence Webster (Historic Sites and Monuments Board of Canada), July 24, 1945, T.L.S., 1p., concerning present life of Malecite and Micmac. Letter of Edwin Tappan Adney, Feb. 9, 1946, T.L.S., 1p., concerning the Celestial Bear, Malecite-Delaware comparisons.
            F&S 2101
          - Malecite -- e. Malecite notes, 1949; III(13D3e); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            Vocabulary list, hunting terms, names of trees. Images note: 7 sketches of pictographs. F&S 2100
        - 4. Mohegan-Mohican
          - Mohegan-Mohican -- a. Mohegans in Maine, 1939; III(10D4a); 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            Reading notes. Images note: sketches and newspaper clippings photographs of tribal living. F&S 2283
          - Mohegan-Mohican -- b. Correspondence with, 1938; III(10D4b); 2 items; Tantaquidgeon, Gladys (Box 7)
            A Connecticut Mohegan Indian, employed by the Government, writes of Shawnee legends and inquires about silk appliqué techniques. Newsclippings.
            F&S 3648
          - Mohegan-Mohican -- c. Miscellaneous notes, 1916-1936; III(10D4c); 19 items (Box 7)
            Commentary on Fidelia Fielding's Texts, 15p. in notebook; notes for 1920 Pequot trip, with Nehantic and Pennacook notes. 3 letters of Hon. Thomas W. Bicknell to Frank G. Speck, Feb. 11, March 1, and March 11, 1924: commentaries on lectures, etc. concerning Indians in Rhode Island. Notes on Mohegan social organization 2p.; 1p. of incomplete letter of Red Wing concerning Indian affairs; miscellaneous Stockbridge notes, 5p.; George Heye to Speck, Feb. 8, 1916, T.L.S., 1p., re publication; J. R. Swanton to Speck, June 22, no year, A.L.S., 3p., concerning his exhibition for Mohegan Stockbridge data, 3p. from published sources; postal card from Princess Pretty War, re dress, Oct. 26, 1943; Ernest E. Rogers to Speck, March 7, 1934, T.L.S., 1p., of New London Hist. Society re Mohegan-Pequot Diary of Speck. Miscellaneous 4p. and 6 cards
            F&S 2284
          - Mohegan-Mohican -- d. Plants at Mohegan, III(10D4d); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            21 trees and uses of their products noted on cards; other cards lacking data.
            F&S 2287
          - Mohegan-Mohican -- e. "Mohegan Indians Deeds", III(10D4e); 1 item; Butler, Eva L. (Box 7)
            22 deeds of seventeenth century signed by Connecticut Mohegan Indians: Connecticut archival sources. A pamphlet of the Industrial Arts Cooperative Service. Contents and index. Images note: 48 ink sketches of totem symbols as signatures. F&S 2285
          - Mohegan-Mohican -- f. [no entry], III(10D4f) (Box 7)
          - Mohegan-Mohican -- g. Mohegan elect chief, n.d.; III(10D4g); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            Copy for a news release.
            F&S 2282
          - Mohegan-Mohican -- h. Mohegan Pequot Texts and vocabulary material, III(10D4h); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 7)
            Mohegan-Pequot texts, 28p. together with a 22p. carbon of another draft. 2p. text and interlinear translation; 2p. phonetic notes; 5p. comparative material and names; 3p. grammatical notes and comparisons; an 1892 vocabulary of Mohegan, 2p. and 1 card. 4p. comparisons.
            F&S 2286
        - 5. Micmac
          - Micmac -- a. Micmac Dance, n.d.; III(13D5a); 2 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            Text with interlinear translation and notes; musical score.
            F&S 2246
          - Micmac -- b. Miscellaneous Micmac notes, 1909-1926; III(13D5b); 26 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            15 bibliographical slips, 8p. of reading notes, concerning hieroglyphics of Micmac. 2p. list of informants; 1p. list of specimens, 1916; 2 copies of printed Micmac mission newspaper, Setaneoei. 1910 and 1920. Note book 1914, 24p. containing words and names of informants; 1 card. 8p. notes including a text in English; 12p. reading notes; 2p. "nominal suffixes"; 1p. bird names of Micmac; 2p. miscellaneous. Letters: Stansbury Hagar to Speck, Jan. 7, 1909, 3p. A.L.S. concerning his Micmac and Cherokee notes; also his bibliography. Same to same, March 8, 1926, 2p. incomplete and 1p. typed copy, concerning his explanation of triangulation to a Micmac chief. John Sark to G. A. Paul, June 30, 1914, 1p. transmits 3p. Micmac text (in mission Micmac). Newell Lyon to Speck, Feb. 21, 1919, 2p. A.L.S. thanking Speck for book. Mrs. Newell Lyon, March 13, 1919, 2p. A.L.S. concerning Lyon's death. News-clipping.
            F&S 2231
          - Micmac -- c. Observations, 1907; III(13D5c); 7 items; Milais, J. J. (Box 9)
            An incomplete article or set of reading excerpts taken after 1922 by Speck from J. J. Millais (1907).
            F&S 2232
          - Micmac -- d. Traveler's account of the Micmac in 1822, n.d.; III(13D5d); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            A brief article.
            F&S 2233
          - Micmac -- e. Micmac Field Notes, 1915; III(13D5e); 9 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            Notebook of 13p. concerning wampum, Hunting Territories; some reference to Passamaquoddy; notebook of 29p. Cape Breton Micmac texts; Newfoundland Micmac data and traditions. 7p. Cape Breton Micmac Texts (English); 1p. map with names of Bear River Band members; 4p, draft of article on Micmac Hunting Territories; 1 envelope of miscellaneous notes; 1 piece birch bark with pictographs inscribed.
            F&S 2230
          - Micmac -- f. Notes from Jesuit Relations, n.d.; III(13D5f); 1 item; Butler, Eva L. (Box 9)
            Extracts concerning the sweat house.
            F&S 2227
          - Micmac -- g. Micmac notes, 1949; III(13D5g); 4 items; Witthoft, J. (Box 9)
            10p. of linguistic notes and vocabulary collected along the Miramichi River. 6p. typed copy by John Witthoft.
            F&S 2247
        - 6. Narraganset
          - Narraganset -- a. Physical measurements of the Narraganset male, 1917; III(14D6a); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            Male 1/4 Nehantic, 1/2 Brotherton (Narraganset).
            F&S 2369
          - Narraganset -- b. Miscellaneous notes, 1916-1926; III(14D6b); 4 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            Comparative vocabulary of Massachusetts, Narraganset, Mohegan, Pequot, and Naugatuck (ca. 30 items); 3 vocabulary lists on cards; 1p. of names. E. B. Delabarre to Speck, May 6, 1920, A.L.S., 2p., prefers Cherokee to Narraganset as explanation of origin of characters on Rhode Island stone. Images note: newspaper clipping photographs peace pipe, native attire, tipi. F&S 2368
        - 7. St. Francis Abenaki
          - St. Francis Abenaki -- a. Conjuring lodge, n.d.; III(14D7a); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            Description.
            F&S 296
          - St. Francis Abenaki -- b. Miscellaneous notes, 1901-1946; III(14D7b); 6 items; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 9)
            Two cards of reading notes; typed copy of Indian poem in English, from John Reade (1887). Also 3p. A.L.S. Frederick S. Dick son to Speck, re Abenaki vocabulary, May 5, 1920, 1p. Typed L.S. Edwin Tappan Adney, February 18, 1946, concerning place names and Maine Indian shamans. Images note: photomechanical print of Montagnais in camp. F&S 297
        - 8. Abenaki